Living in the heart of Sudan's Dafu region, the Masalit aren't just a community.
They are a force of nature.
Their resilience is, however, facing their toughest test yet.
In the last few months, thousands have been killed by the Rapid Support Forces militia.
Their crime being ethnic Africa.
This is how a genocide looks like.
Although UN agencies have reported about this senseless madras rampage from the Rapid Support Forces,
the UN Security Council hasn't uttered a single word about it.
Are they waiting for more people to die before they declare this a genocide?
How many more lives of the Masalit community members and other ethnic African community members in Dafu
have to be lost before the UN can take decisive action?
Haven't they learned from what happened in Rwanda about 20 years ago?
The Rapid Support Forces, then known as Janjaid Militia,
executed a genocide in Dafu and killed about 300,000 people.
That genocide targeted black Sudanese people.
The ghosts of this solid past are back with a madras bang.
Masalit life is a tapestry woven with music, laughter, and rich history.
We must not allow this tapestry to be torn asunder.
We must not allow more lives to be lost.